When you were at school, the last thing you probably wanted to do was spend your weekends going to work.
当你还在上学的时候，你最不想做的事情可能就是在周末去工作了。
There was homework to do, sport to play and fun to be had.
有作业要做，有运动要参加，还有各种好玩的事情。
But our parents probably persuaded us to find a job to earn some money and get some life experience.
但我们的父母可能会劝说我们找份工作，赚点钱，积累一些生活经验。
When I was a teenager I had a paper round: delivering newspapers to people's homes.
我十几岁的时候有一份送报纸的工作：把报纸投递到人们家里。
I then progressed to a Saturday job in a supermarket: stacking shelves and working at the checkout.
后来进展到去超市找了份周六的兼职工作：整理货架（stacking shelves）和在收银台（checkout）工作。
Today in the UK you are allowed to work from the age of 13, and many children do take up part-time jobs.
如今在英国，13岁就可以工作了，很多孩子也确实会去做兼职。
It's one of those things that is seen almost as a rite of passage.
这几乎被看作是一种成人仪式（rite of passage）。
It's a taste of independence and sometimes a useful thing to put on your CV.
这是一种对独立的体验，而且有时候把它写在简历上也很有用。
Teenagers agree that it teaches valuable lessons about working with adults and also about managing your money.
青少年们都认为，做兼职可以学到与成年人共事以及理财的宝贵经验。
So, that's no bad thing!
所以，这没什么不好的！
Some research has shown that not taking on a Saturday or holiday job could be detrimental to a person later on.
一些研究表明，不做周六或假期兼职工作可能会对一个人日后产生不利的（detrimental）影响。
A 2015 study by the UK Commission on Employment and Skills found that not participating in part-time work at school age had been blamed by employers' organisations for young adults being ill-prepared for full-time employment.
英国就业与技能委员会（UK Commission on Employment and Skills）在2015年的一项研究发现，雇主组织认为，青少年在上学期间不参加兼职工作是导致年轻人对全职工作准备不足的原因。
But despite this, recent statistics have shown that the number of schoolchildren in the UK with a part-time job has fallen by a fifth in the past five years.
但尽管如此，最近的统计数据显示，在过去五年里，英国有兼职工作的中小学生数量下降了五分之一。
So, does this mean that British teenagers are now more afraid of hard graft?
那么，这是否意味着英国的青少年现在更害怕努力工作（hard graft）了呢？
Probably not.
可能不是。
Some experts feel that young people feel going out to work will hinder their performance at school, and they are under more pressure now to study hard and get good exam results - and a good job in the long term.
一些专家认为，年轻人觉得出去工作会妨碍（hinder）他们在学校的表现，而且他们现在面临着更大的压力，要努力学习，取得好成绩——从长远来看，还要找到一份好工作。
However, Geoff Barton, general secretary of the Association of School and College Leaders, told BBC News that "Properly regulated part-time work is a good way of helping young people learn skills that they will need in their working lives."
然而，学校和学院领导协会（Association of School and College Leaders）的秘书长杰夫・巴顿（Geoff Barton）告诉BBC新闻：“适当规范的兼职工作是帮助年轻人学习他们在工作生活中所需技能的好方法。”
In reality, it's all about getting the right balance between doing part-time work and having enough time to study and rest.
实际上，关键在于在做兼职工作和有足够的时间学习和休息之间找到正确的平衡。
Many young people actually want to work because it gives them a sense of freedom.
许多年轻人实际上是想工作的，因为这能给他们一种自由感。
One 13 year-old girl called Rachel, who has a Saturday job in a shop, told the BBC that "I enjoy my job because I'm earning money and it helps my confidence speaking to people and socialising with people I work with."
一个名叫瑞秋（Rachel）的13岁女孩在一家商店做周六兼职，她告诉BBC：“我喜欢我的工作，因为我在挣钱，而且这有助于我在与人交谈和与同事社交时增强信心。”
That seems like something worth getting up for on a Saturday morning.
这似乎是一件值得在周六早上起床去做的事情。
Did you do a part-time job when you were at school?
你上学的时候做过兼职工作吗？